# 哈喽大家好
Hi everyone
# 我伯爷昨天饭煮多了放在冰箱里面冻得比较硬
My uncle cooked too much rice yesterday, which we refrigerated and has got hard
# 这个冷饭只有拿来炒饭哦
Cold rice is only good for making fried rice
# 做蛋炒饭
Fried rice with egg
# 然后准备了一些鸡蛋
I also prepared some eggs
# 再加一些这个辣椒来做一个香葱版本的蛋炒饭吧
Let's cook 'fried rice with egg and spring onion' with the chili pepper here
# 我们这个鸡蛋的话打进去不用搅它
We don't need to stir the egg now
# 直接下锅煎就可以了
Just fry it in the wok
# 煎香了再用来炒
When the egg smells good, we can use it for stir-frying
# 这个鸡蛋就打好了
The eggs are done
# 这个辣椒我们直接切成颗粒就好了
Simply cut the chili pepper into dices
# 其实也不是很辣噶这个辣椒
This chili is actually not spicy, huh?
# 这个辣椒不辣
No, not spicy
# 再切一个大红椒配一下颜色
Cut a red bell pepper for the color
# 同样的也是切成颗粒
Similarly, cut into dices
# 辣椒籽也不要浪费了
Don't throw away the seeds
# 其实辣椒籽炒在里面很香的
Actually the dish smells very nice with the seeds
# 这个又不辣的
This is not spicy at all
# 我们在酒店里面做的话这个辣椒籽是不要得
In restaurants, we usually discard the seeds
# 因为影响美观
Because the dish doesn't look good with them
# 我们最后再切点小葱
Finally, cut some spring onion
# 就多放一点
Let me add more spring onion
# 我四伯爷喜欢吃葱
Because my uncle likes it
# 放在一边
Put aside
# 好 可以了
Ok. Done
# 你来帮我拿一下鸡蛋
Please take the egg
# 好嘛 好
Ok. Sure
# 我们这个鸡蛋下锅不要去搅散直接这样煎
Don't stir the egg after you add it into the wok. Just fry it like this
# 煎到它香为止
Until you can smell the aroma
# 然后煎香了之后把它翻过来
Flip the egg when it smells nice
# 四伯爷这样炒的比你柴火灶炒的更好吃哦
Uncle, the dish cooked here will taste better than those cooked on your wood stove
# 当然哦火要大就大要小就小
Of course. You can easily tune the heat
# 好了
Done
# 诶呀 好香哦
Wow. Smells great
# 看到没四伯爷锅里都还有锅气
See it, uncle? There's still 'wok hei' (smoke) in the wok
# 来四伯爷
Come on, uncle
# 吃饭
Time for meal!
# 尝哈看我给你炒的炒饭
Try the fried rice that I cooked for you
# 这是你的碗 我给你舀起
This is your bowl. Let me scoop some for you
# 来嘛伯娘
Come on, aunt
# 你先尝一下看吃得惯不
Just take a bite first to see if you are used to it
# 来伯爷
This is yours, uncle
# 嗯 好香哦
Umm. Delicious
# 该好吃噶
Tasty indeed, huh?
# 嗯
Yes
# 辣不辣哦 四伯爷
Is it spicy, uncle?
# 不辣 一点儿都不辣
Nope. Not at all
# 这个蛋炒饭比上次去成都吃的那个更好吃
This fried rice is even better than the one that I had in Chengdu last time
# 这个青椒的清香味才安逸
The clear aroma of the green chili pepper is really nice
# 我们自己在家里面吃蛋炒饭
When cooking fried rice at home
# 这个鸡蛋不用搅
You don't actually need to stir the egg
# 直接给它慢慢煎香了再来炒
Just fry it first. Then stir-fry other ingredients
# 然后炒蛋炒饭最重要的一个就是火要散得开
In addition, the most important point in cooking fried rice is that, the heat should be uniform
# 然后不要太大的冲劲
Avoid sudden temperature change #请检查这里
# 就是让这个铁锅保持有锅气
That is, to keep the 'wok hei' in the wok
# 然后这个饭在里 面炒
Such that you can stir-fry the rice
# 炒饭如果没有锅气就不会香
Without the 'wok hei', the rice won't be delicious
# 所以我敢说这个炒饭的话比四伯爷在土灶上面炒的更香
So I bet this fried rice is better than those cooked on my uncle's wood stove
# 嗯
Yep
# 还有就是我们蛋炒饭不要拿热饭去炒
One more thing, don't use hot rice for cooking fried rice
# 热饭的话炒出来不香
Hot rice won't taste good after stir-frying
# 必须是冷饭
It has to be cold rice
# 而且这个冷饭还要偏硬一点点
Also the cold rice should be relatively hard
# 太软了也不行
It won't work if it's too soft/mushy
# 软了煎起不散酥都嘛
Mushy rice won't turn out fluffy like this
# 就是坨坨货
It will stick together and clump up
# 好啦本期视频就到这里
Ok. That's the end of this video
# 喜欢的可以在家里面试一下
If you like it, please try at home
# 拜拜
Bye-bye!